Hi everybody. I'm John Kiriakou and
welcome back to the briefing room.
Before we jump into the news and today
is a day packed with news. I want to say
thank you again for liking, for
subscribing, for commenting, for
following and telling your family and
friends about the podcast. We are
growing by leaps and bounds and it's
just because of you. So thank you very,
very much for that.
Well, let's jump in. There is a lot to
go over. We've got a packed show today.
First, Vice President J.D. Vance
carried out a remarkable interview with
Joe Rogan. Why did he suddenly admit
that the Trump administration has
mishandled the Epstein files? And what
does that tell us about what is
happening inside the White House? To
tell you the truth, there are two
equally plausible explanations for this
and we're going to go over that. Then a
major escalation in the Middle East over
the last 24 hours that could send gas
prices soaring before the midterm
elections. And finally, we'll look ahead
to the midterm elections and what the
surprising success of democratic
socialists in recent primaries could
mean for the political map in 2026. And
really the basic question is, is this
even really a positive for the
Democrats? And finally, I want to make
one quick note and that is to
recognize the death early this morning
of former CIA director James Woolsey at
the age of 86.
I I knew James Woolsey.
He was a controversial figure.
And one of the reasons why I wanted to
bring his death up is that he died of a
stroke but after suffering for 4 years
from Havana syndrome. So we'll talk
about that for a minute.
In this A block, let's start with J.D.
Vance and Joe Rogan and the Epstein
files. So we're going to dig into these
Epstein files because of the Iran war.
It's been a long time since the media
could really focus on the Epstein files
in any meaningful way. But this week
there was a major development. The Vice
President, J.D. Vance, went on the Joe
Rogan podcast, and he openly admitted
that the Trump administration mishandled
the release of the files. We'll play
that clip in just a second, but there's
a lot that shocked me about that
admission that I want to say first.
In the intelligence field, you learn to
pay very close attention when a
government voluntarily changes its
story, especially on matters related to
national security and state secrets.
That's what I want to dig into today.
Let's start off by saying this.
The vote in the House of Representatives
to release the Epstein files was 419
to 1.
In the Senate, it was 99 to nothing.
And then the president signed it into
law.
And then as soon as he signed it into
law, he said, "You know what? Tough
luck. I'm not going to release anything.
What are you going to do about it? What
are you going to sue me?"
And what can we do about it? The answer
is nothing. And so, 3 million pages of
documents were released. That leaves
another 3 to 3 and 1/2 million pages
that have not been released. And
Marjorie Taylor Greene, if she's to be
believed, said that the president told
her to her face that he will never
release the remaining documents, quote,
"Because it'll hurt my friends."
As a quick refresher, we are more than 7
months past that deadline when the White
House was supposed to release the
remaining 3 to 3 and 1/2 million pages
of those Epstein files after Congress
passed the Epstein Files Transparency
Act sponsored by Republican Thomas
Massie and Democrat Ro Khanna,
requiring,
by law, the force of law, requiring the
Justice Department to release the
Epstein files no later than December
19th of last year.
The administration still has not
produced many of the documents that
supporters expected. But even more
striking is the political fallout for
Republicans who supported the Epstein
files release. Republicans who supported
transparency. Thomas Massie, the
Republican of Kentucky,
became one of the Trump administration's
top political targets. The White House
went after him so hard outside super
PACs, mostly those affiliated with
AIPAC, spent $35 million to kick him out
of his $180,000
a year job in Congress.
And Donald Trump personally flew to his
district to his district to rally
against him.
Marjorie Taylor Greene was forced to
resign from Congress after years of
being one of Donald Trump's most loyal
supporters. Indeed, her son,
a high schooler, was receiving death
threats. And when she went to the
president to ask for help, some kind of
protection, maybe Secret Service, he
told her tough luck. You should have
thought about that before you opened
your mouth.
Representative Nancy Mace of South
Carolina, she ran for the governorship
of South Carolina and came in fifth. A
sitting congresswoman came in fifth
after losing Donald Trump's endorsement.
And Representative Lauren Boebert was
brought into the situation room for a
meeting with senior White House
officials, including FBI Director Kash
Patel and then Attorney General Pam
Bondi, to pressure her to remove her
name from that discharge petition. She's
still in Congress.
I don't know if she made some sort of a
deal with the White House. With that
said, neither the Republicans nor the
Democrats take her seriously.
But each one of those Republicans,
except for Boebert, are about to be out
of a job or are already out of a job.
Which makes it all the more surprising
when J.D. Vance goes on to the Joe Rogan
podcast
and says this. Let's go to that clip.
>> We mishandled the Epstein release.
Guilty. We did mishandle, especially the
communications of it.
>> What do you think should have been done?
>> I think that we should have just dropped
everything at the very beginning and
like obviously takes a little time to
review the stuff, to find the stuff, to
redact things where you have victims and
so forth. We should have just done it as
quickly as possible.
>> But some of the stuff that was redacted,
some of the names that were redacted
weren't victims.
>> So yeah, I I I I've looked into this and
my understanding of this, having looked
at a lot of this but not all of it,
is that
it is sometimes hard to draw a
distinction between victim and
co-conspirator. And like let me
highlight this in a very sort of
obvious way.
Ro Khanna, who's been one of the most
one of the loudest voices on the Epstein
file, well, he became very loud on the
Epstein files the minute Donald Trump
became president, didn't seem to care
about it during the Biden
administration. He actually brought one
of the Epstein victims, I think to the
State of the Union last year or maybe it
was the year before last.
Well, like that victim,
and I'm not accusing, I'm not saying she
wasn't a victim,
uh I don't know anything about her
particular case, she was also listed as
a co-conspirator in some of these
documents, right?
>> Maybe she was, maybe she wasn't. We
should note that Ro Khanna is not the
enemy here. And Donald Trump has already
been president in a previous term. Why
didn't he release the Epstein documents
then? You can't blame this on Ro Khanna,
just like you can't blame it on Thomas
Massie. You got to blame it on Joe Biden
and Donald Trump because the buck has to
has to stop somewhere.
So,
Vance says that that quote, "We
mishandled the Epstein files." There are
several other other things that shocked
to about this clip. Number one, he's the
sitting Vice President of the United
States. If he's talking as if the
Epstein scandal is is over and that this
is the hot wash that we're going back
and we're looking at well, you know,
this is the way it could have been done.
This is an open case.
There are still three to three and a
half million pages under the FBI's
control that have not been made public.
Three to three and a half million pages
that the president said will never be
released because they would embarrass
his friends.
Well,
there are still also many witnesses to
be subpoenaed by Congress.
Uh let's talk about Alan Dershowitz.
Alan Dershowitz is 86 years old and
admitted to getting a a massage from a
16-year-old girl
and his defense was he kept his
underwear on.
But Republicans on the House Oversight
Committee are not even close to calling
witnesses to to testify, let alone
subpoenaing witnesses. So, it's striking
to hear the Vice President of the United
States speak as if the only remaining
issue in the to get this message out.
Number two, the pivot to saying that Ro
Khanna, of all people,
didn't care about this under Biden.
Sure, Democrats were not exactly
champions of releasing these files under
Biden, probably because it would have
embarrassed friends of theirs.
But it leaves this out. Republicans
campaigned
on releasing the files. This was a
campaign issue that was used against
Kamala Harris. We will release the
files. Well, they're the ones who
promised to release the files, which
made it much more obvious that there was
a scandal when they suddenly reversed
course after giving out Epstein files
binders to MAGA influencers. You
remember that?
Third, and perhaps most important, J.D.
Vance is someone who very much still has
a seat at the table for all things
intelligence. Of course, he's not in
charge of the FBI, but he is close
enough
to know the internal strategy at the
FBI. He knows the political
calculations. And if the White House
wanted him delivering a different
message,
he wouldn't be going on the Joe Rogan
show and saying, "Well, we made a
mistake. This is the way it should have
been. Blah, blah, blah."
There's no way
that J.D. Vance of all people is going
rogue here. My assumption is that this
was approved. Let's talk about that for
a second. Maybe it was intended to cool
off frustration among the MAGA base.
That that's certainly possible. Maybe it
was an effort to create some distance
between Vance and the rollout heading
into 2028. Maybe it was both. Look at it
this way. J.D. Vance is the Republican
Party's leading candidate for president
in 2028. I personally think he's not
going to be the nominee. He's very
young.
He can run for president every 4 years
for the next 40 years if he wants. I
think the nominee's going to be Marco
Rubio. But right now, today, J.D. Vance
is the front-runner. And I think that he
has been given permission to stake out a
slightly different position
on this issue while not pointing the
finger at Donald Trump.
He's saying, "Yeah, we made mistakes.
Yeah, if it was up to me, I would have
done it differently, but you know, I'm
just the vice president."
Now, let's look at what to me
was the even more remarkable exchange.
Check out this clip.
>> Well, most people think he was Mossad.
>> Yeah, Mossad or CIA or some other deep
state, whether in America, Israel, or
another country.
>> Or or both.
Um
You know, look, was he he clearly had
connections to the upper the highest
levels of American intelligence. He
clearly had connections to the highest
levels of Israeli intelligence. And yes,
I've asked, were there like
were there documents connecting Jeffrey
Epstein directly to our intelligence
agencies or anybody else's? And the
answer is no, but if that should
existed, it wouldn't exist in 2026.
>> A couple of uh months ago, I went on the
Piers Morgan show to talk about this
specific issue and I said in
in no
equivocal terms that Jeffrey Epstein was
a Mossad access agent. All the evidence
points to it. It makes perfect sense.
It's as though you opened up the
intelligence textbook and looked up
access agent, Jeffrey Epstein's picture
would be there.
Um that led to multiple death threats.
One from Rabbi Simcha Scholar of New
York City. I'm calling you out, you
bastard, who said to me that there's a
place in the ovens for me and for Jew
haters like me.
Shame on you protecting a pedophile and
a child trafficker just because he
happens to be Jewish. Let's talk about
Epstein as a Mossad agent. Of course, he
was a Mossad agent. He probably also was
working for the CIA and the FBI and MI5
and MI6 and the Germans.
And we know, thanks to the 3 million
pages of the Epstein files that have
already been released that he actively
sought a meeting with Vladimir Putin.
The Russians said, "No, thank you."
So, of course, he was a Mossad agent.
Let's call a spade a spade. The Mossad
spies on us every single day all across
America. Just 3 weeks ago,
the Defense Intelligence Agency, DIA,
sent around an all-hands email
telling all DIA employees to be
especially careful right now because the
Israelis have stepped up their espionage
activities against the United States and
the US intelligence community. But this
comment by J.D. Vance stopped me in my
tracks. Not because J.D. Vance raised
the possibility that Epstein had
intelligence connections. People have
been saying that for years. He
acknowledges there's no documentary
evidence tying Epstein to the CIA, to
the Mossad, or other intelligence
services. Then, almost in the same
breath,
and I don't know if you caught it,
he says that if such documents ever
existed,
they probably wouldn't exist today. Did
you notice that in that response to to
Joe Rogan?
He essentially accused the CIA
of obstruction of justice,
of destroying documents. That's a
felony.
And he just said it matter-of-factly. I
don't know if we've ever had someone in
the White House openly speculate about
whether intelligence is so flawed
publicly on a podcast. It's true that
the CIA has destroyed documents in the
past. Just Google MK Ultra. It'll make
your hair stand up if you don't know
anything about it.
No one knows this better than I do.
But it puts us in a tough position of
trying to figure out who's not being
honest about the files cuz somebody's
clearly lying.
Is it the CIA
or is it J.D. Vance
or J.D. Vance talking to us?
This also sheds a little bit of light on
one question. Why did J.D. Vance get the
green light from the White House to do
this podcast?
Probably because in the documents
there's no evidence linking Epstein to
foreign intelligence. There's a lot of
inference,
but no documentary evidence. And that's
one of the few things Democrats would be
willing to work with Republicans on to
keep private.
Don't forget, this is not a partisan
issue.
The Republicans are in the Epstein files
up to their necks just as much as the
Democrats are. They're both corrupt.
They're two sides of the same coin.
But many people are raising the
question,
is this just J.D. Vance trying to throw
a bone to the MAGA base to help his own
presidential chances in 2028? I'll do my
best to do justice to both arguments.
Maybe it did take a lot of arm-twisting
for J.D. Vance to say this publicly
against the will of the White House. But
one very big hole in his claim that he's
an Epstein truth-teller, if J.D. Vance
genuinely believes that there are
unanswered questions about whether
Jeffrey Epstein had ties to a foreign
intelligence service, specifically
Mossad,
he's in one of the very few positions in
government where he can actually ask
those questions and demand answers.
He had access to the Director of
National Intelligence.
He has the CIA Director on speed dial.
He can ask the FBI Director anytime he
wants. He can request briefings at the
highest levels of classification.
He can push investigators to determine
whether credible evidence exists.
But instead, he just decided to
speculate on the Joe Rogan podcast.
From an intelligence standpoint, I
always pay attention to the difference
between evidence and messaging. Right
now, J.D. Vance is offering messaging.
He's not presenting any new evidence.
The evidence is probably there.
They're just not allowing us to see it.
And that's an important distinction.
A couple of questions that I'm often
asked about this issue, do presidents
and vice presidents actually read
intelligence documents like the Epstein
files? That answer is no.
Um one of the things that I learned
early on at the CIA
is the president just doesn't have the
time to read everything that
you or I would want him to read. That's
why the president's daily brief is
never, ever, ever more than 16 pages
long, ever.
And I remember writing an article once,
one of the first articles that I wrote
for the president's daily brief, and
having my boss sit me down, look me in
the eye, and say, "The president doesn't
give a
about your opinions.
The president wants to read this entire
story in one paragraph.
Make it fit into one paragraph. There
aren't enough hours in the day for a
president or vice president to go
through something like the Epstein
files. Another question is, do I think
this is enough for J.D. Vance to win the
2028 Republican presidential nomination,
or will it take a lot more to please the
MAGA base? I think the MAGA base is very
upset about a lot more than the Epstein
files.
I think the MAGA base is upset about
this war of choice that we're fighting
in Iran right now, with no exit strategy
at all, and gas at four and a half
dollars a gallon. Look, I spent my
career in the CIA. I know exactly how
easy it is to find someone when you have
their name and just a little bit of
patience. And here's what should scare
you. These days, you don't need to be a
spy to do it. Your name, your home
address, your phone number, details
about your family, it's all sitting
right there online, compiled by data
brokers and sold to anyone with a credit
card. I've made my share of enemies over
the years, God knows. And since going
public with the torture program, I've
got a lot more strangers who know who I
am. So, safety and security are not
abstract to me. They are daily concerns.
All that personal data floating around
out out there on the internet has
real-world consequences. And honestly,
most people have no idea how exposed
they are. That's why I I
use DeleteMe.
DeleteMe is a subscription service that
removes your personal information from
hundreds of data brokers online. You
sign up, you tell them exactly what
information you want taken down, and
their experts handle it from there.
They send you regular personalized
privacy reports showing what they found,
where they found it, and what they
removed. And it's not a one-time thing.
DeleteMe is always working in the
background, constantly monitoring and
removing the information you don't want
out there. In plain terms, they do the
hard work of wiping your and your
family's personal information off of
these broker sites. For someone like me,
that peace of mind is worth a lot. So,
take control of your data and keep your
private life private by signing up for
DeleteMe.
Now at a special discount for our
listeners, today get 20% off your
DeleteMe plan when you go to
joindeleteme.com/jkbr
and use promo code jkbr
at checkout. The only way to get 20% off
is to go to joindeleteme.com/jkbr
and enter code jkbr at checkout. That
again is joindeleteme.com/jkbr
code jkbr. Folks, I received an email a
couple of days ago um asking a question
about something that I said in the last
episode of Briefing Room. I misspoke in
the last episode of Briefing Room where
I said that this is the only official
John Kiriakou podcast. That's not true.
Somehow I forgot about
a very important thing that I'm doing,
and that's called John Kiriakou's Dead
Drop. That's a podcast that appears on
Apple Podcasts and Spotify. I am
immensely grateful, crazy grateful for
the 3 million downloads that we've had.
But that one, John Kiriakou's Dead Drop,
it's a storytelling podcast. I wasn't
thinking about storytelling. I was
thinking about news. This, John
Kiriakou's Briefing Room, is the only
news show that we do, and we do this
twice a week. We're going to add a third
one with Q&A's. We'll talk about that in
a few minutes. But thank you for that
email and for allowing me the the
opportunity to clarify.
I now wanted to talk about Yemen again,
one of the most overlooked
countries in the world, one of the most
important countries in the Middle East
vis-a-vis national security.
And I also believe this is one of the
most underreported stories of the week.
So let's move on to Yemen, which could
be
the match
that ignites at least a regional war
across the Middle East. Yemen's
Iran-aligned Houthis announced on Monday
that they were imposing a naval blockade
against Saudi Arabia.
A move that could launch the price of
gas way past where it is right now.
Let's take a look at this clip from Good
Morning America.
>> This morning, new fears the war with
Iran could be expanding with the
Iran-backed Houthis from Yemen now
threatening to block Saudi oil from
transiting another key waterway. This
one connecting the Red Sea to the Indian
Ocean. With traffic in the Strait of
Hormuz already slowing to a crawl,
cutting off the Red Sea could cause oil
prices to spike even further and gas
prices now more than $4 a gallon as
well.
>> I'm proud to say I called this a week
ago.
Uh
Listen, one of the goals with this show
is to predict the news before anybody
else reports it. That was a a big
example. I'm I'm one of the few people
inside or outside government that really
follows Yemen closely.
Um check this out. I think this is just
nuts. This is what the Houthis are
actually broadcasting
to Saudi ships on open channels. Listen
to this.
>> This is calling you on channel 16.
According to the decision of Yemeni
armed forces in the date of July 202026,
we warn all ships belonging to Saudi
enemy to proceed via the Red Sea and
Gulf of Aden.
In case of non-compliance of Yemeni
armed forces decision, all ships will be
in our target. Over.
>> This requires a little bit of
explanation. Let's go back to 1990,
August the 2nd.
Iraqi troops invade and occupy Kuwait.
The Kuwaiti ruling family flees to
uh Taif, Saudi Arabia.
It just so happened that Yemen and Cuba
were non-permanent members of the United
Nations Security Council that year. And
so Secretary of State James Baker went
to the Yemenis and the Cubans, more the
Yemenis, and said, "Listen, we are at a
historic crossroads. You have to do the
right thing and you have to vote yes on
the United Nations Security Council's um
uh resolution to use force to kick the
Iraqis out of Kuwait. The whole world is
on our side. You need to be on the right
side, too."
And the Yemenis voted no.
The Yemenis decided to throw their lot
in with Saddam Hussein.
There were 2 million Yemeni workers in
Saudi Arabia at that time. every last
one of them was expelled from Saudi
Arabia and the world has never been the
same.
I flew into Yemen on my very first trip
to the country in June of 1991.
I flew to Sana, the capital, from Jeddah
along the Red Sea coast of Saudi Arabia.
For 20 minutes before the plane landed,
you could see
people living in cardboard boxes
or in makeshift lean-tos, no roofs,
tents,
2 million people thrown out of Saudi
Arabia on the same day. These are people
that can't afford shoes, that can't
afford food for their children and
water. To make matters worse,
as recently as the late 1970s, Yemen was
a net food exporter. And they decided to
stop growing food so they could replace
all the food with something called qat,
q a t. Qat is like coca, but not as
potent. They chew it all day long and
it's a stimulant. It's like drinking a
pot of coffee.
Well, now you see people sitting in
these little They look like tree houses
with old rifles guarding their qat.
Their children don't have food, but
there's plenty of qat to chew. Well,
then all these 2 million workers were
expelled from Saudi Arabia. There's no
food, there's no water, there are no
jobs, there's no housing.
I've been to Yemen five times over the
years and every single time I go, it's
worse than the previous time.
For decades, the country was led by a
president named Ali Abdullah Saleh.
Saleh was close to Saudi Arabia. He was
also close to the United States.
But then he split with us on this Saddam
Hussein vote.
Immediately a Yemeni civil war started
and it wasn't just, you know, the good
guys versus the bad guys. It was a
multi-part civil war and you have
Al-Qaeda
fighting as part of that civil war.
Osama bin Laden's family originated in
Yemen in the eastern part of Yemen in an
area called the Hadramaut. Hadramaut
comes from two Arabic words. Hadar,
which means visitation vegetation, maut
means dead.
It says it's called dead vegetation
because it's so dry, literally nothing
can live there. Animals don't even live
there.
Well, that's where Al-Qaeda was based in
Yemen in this no man's land that nobody
else could go to. They began attacking
the central government. In South Yemen,
the former communists began attacking
the central government and the Shia
Muslims in northwestern Yemen began
attacking the the central government.
Ali Ali Abdullah Saleh fled to Saudi
Arabia and took refuge there. The Saudis
reluctantly gave it to him, but somebody
was able to sneak into the palace uh
that he was living in and they planted a
bomb and it quite literally blew his
head off.
So, Ali Abdullah Saleh
no longer exists.
The last time I went to Yemen was in
2011 and I had gone there from Djibouti,
which as I mentioned in the last episode
is just about 9 miles across the water.
Something called the Bab el-Mandeb where
the Horn of Africa almost meets the uh
the southwestern tip of the Arabian
Peninsula, right there.
And when I got into a cab in Sana'a, I
said to the to the driver, "So, how are
things going?" And he said, "Oh, things
are rough right now." He said the the uh
the Houthis are attacking the capital
city. And I said, "Yeah, I've read about
that. It's terrible." And he said,
"They're using drones against us." And I
said,
"The Houthis don't have drones."
And then I thought to myself,
"But we do."
In 2011, we were already involved in a
war
in Yemen in 2011, and nobody knew about
it. Thank you, Barack Obama.
Another American secret war.
So, now here we are all these years
later. The Houthis have overthrown
the um
the Yemeni government. They have taken
control of the Yemeni government, even
if they don't control the whole of
Yemen.
Uh they control the most important parts
of Yemen. So, what are they threatening
here specifically?
They're specifically threatening to blow
up
ships coming in and out
of Saudi Arabia, which really is Jeddah.
Most of those ships are oil tankers.
But a good number of them are cargo
ships that are that are have come
through the Suez Canal and are going to
transit the Bab al-Mandab. If the
Yemenis do this,
it's going to force ships to go instead
of going through the Suez Canal and the
Bab al-Mandab to go all the way around
Africa,
which adds 30 days to the trip and
billions of gallons of fuel.
So,
we're talking about the entire planet
going into a recession
and having to fight what's going to be
out of control inflation
because this little group of bandits has
closed the Bab al-Mandab.
This is going to be a very serious
thing. So, how did the Saudis respond?
>> Well, they essentially can't. I mean,
there's a Saudi navy for what that's
worth, but the Saudi military has been
fighting the Houthis for more than a
decade, and they lost. The Houthis won.
Another thing that I learned when I was
living in Saudi Arabia is that
even though the Saudis, you know,
economically, geographically, physically
dominate
the Yemenis, and especially the Houthis,
the Houthis are fierce fighters, and
they're not afraid of it anybody, but
the Saudis are afraid of them.
And so, this is going to be a serious
problem for the Saudis.
Let's talk for a second though about the
Israeli factor.
You might remember
6, 8, 10 months ago, whatever it
whatever it is, the Israeli government
recognized an area of Somalia called
Somaliland as an independent country.
It's not an independent country, even
though many of us, including me, wish
that it was. It's not an independent
country.
The Israelis are the only country in the
world that recognize Somaliland as
independent.
That's great for Somaliland. There's an
Israeli embassy now in Somaliland. So,
what do the Israelis get out of it?
They get an airbase.
They get an airbase that's about 100
miles from the Houthis.
And so, if Israeli shipping
is threatened in the Bab el Mandeb, they
are going to unleash F-35s and attempt
to blow the Houthis back to the Stone
Age. That's been tried in the past. It
doesn't work.
I think what we're going to end up
seeing here
is crimes against humanity.
We're going to see the port of Hodeidah
bombed repeatedly. And the last time the
Israelis did this, they bombed schools,
they bombed And the Saudis, they're just
as guilty. Schools, hospitals, children,
private homes, it makes no difference.
They just bombed everything.
I think we're going to see more of that.
I want to add one other thing, two other
things. Number one, if the Saudis are
attacked,
the Bahrainis are going to jump in
because the Bahrainis and the Saudis are
joined at the hip. And if the Bahrainis
jump in, the Emirates probably will jump
in. Now, the Emirates appear to have
negotiated their own private one-to-one
deal with Iran. We'll give you $3
million in cash if you stop bombing us.
And the Iranians stopped.
But the Saudis and the Emirates, even
though they were on different sides of
the of the fight in Yemen,
um
if the Saudis were endangered, I think
the Emirates would jump in on the side
of the Saudis.
And then we have a full-fledged regional
war.
You have Saudi Arabia,
Kuwait, Bahrain,
the United Arab Emirates, Oman, Jordan,
and Israel
against Iran
and Yemen.
Qatar's going to try to remain neutral.
Oman's going to try to remain neutral,
but this is going to be a full-fledged
regional war. I want to add one other
thing.
Um back in 2010, I was working
I was working on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee, and a local think
tank asked me if I would um
participate in a debate on Yemen.
I said, "Sure, why not?"
And so, you know, I I generally never
prepare for these things. I figure if if
I don't know these issues by now, I'm
never going to know them. I'm supposed
to be an expert, so I just have to rely
on my own knowledge and my own
background.
I go to this event on Capitol Hill
having no idea that my debate is against
Senator Susan Collins.
So, she's there with a whole army of
aides, and she's got her notes, and
she's reading her note cards, and I'm
just sitting there on the stage, you
know, like looking at my watch and
looking at the crowd and waving at
people.
And it comes time to to debate.
And I essentially said in the debate
what I just told you.
That the Yemenis are consistently
underestimated.
That they are scrappy and tough and mean
and fierce fighters, and they are not
afraid of anybody. And even though Saudi
Arabia is bigger and richer and more
powerful, that the Yemenis were going to
win.
And I said,
the US long said that it had no national
interests in Yemen. Indeed, it has
national interests. It's
counterterrorism,
counter piracy,
and open trade through the Bab
al-Mandab.
Well, Senator uh
Collins disagreed with me. Okay, that's
fine. At the end, I got up, I shook her
hand, and I went home.
The next day, John Kerry, who was my
boss, walks into my office and says,
"Did you debate Senator Collins last
night?" And I said, "I did. And if I may
say so, I kicked her ass."
He didn't think that was funny.
And he just said to me, "Don't ever do
that again."
And then he walked out. Well, you know
what? I didn't work for John Kerry too
much after that, so I did whatever the
heck I pleased. What if the way money
works is about to change? Not someday.
Not hypothetically. I mean right now.
China and the United States are both
making moves that suggest we could be
heading towards something that the world
hasn't seen in more than 50 years. A
return to gold-backed money or something
very close to it. China is shutting down
paper gold trading at four of its
biggest banks, all on the same day. And
they're building a new system that
settles in physical gold instead. On our
side, the government is sitting on more
than 8,000 tons of gold that's still
valued at $42 an ounce.
That's on the books. Legislation to fix
that is already in Congress. If both
superpowers start anchoring their
currencies to gold, what happens to the
price?
And more importantly, what happens to
every dollar in your retirement that
isn't backed by anything at all? That's
the question a free report from American
Alternative Assets answers. It's called
The Day Money Changes Forever.
And if you have an IRA or a 401k, you
need to read it right now. Get your free
copy at johnlovesgold.com.
That's johnlovesgold.com
or you can call toll free at
1-888-GOLD-053.
Politico reported this week that the
Republicans have their issue to use
against Democrats in the midterms. The
issue is this, Republicans are going to
call the Democrats
communists.
Like it's 1950.
Communists.
I read my hometown newspaper every day,
the Newcastle News. I don't know why,
but I do.
And there was an article in this paper
about this uh Mexican restaurant that's
up near where my mom and dad used to
live. I love this place, El Canelo.
Terrific food, great staff. They're all
Mexican immigrants and they are
magnificent and they've done well and
they've opened like four or five
restaurants around the whole area now.
So, somebody wrote in the paper that
they left a tip
and the waiter told them, "Oh, the tips
all go to the owner."
That's not cool.
And then in the comment section,
somebody wrote, "That's socialism."
I never comment because most people are
idiots.
I felt compelled to comment, and I said,
"Actually, that's capitalism. Socialism
would be if the workers owned the
restaurant."
The Republicans are banking on the
notion that Americans
don't have any idea what the difference
is between socialism and communism. I'll
tell you another quick story.
When I was still married, um I spent a
Thanksgiving at the home of my ex-wife's
cousins. Lovely people. They would
always have a big bash, and on this
particular occasion, they uh invited a
neighbor over, an older woman in her in
her mid-80s.
She just sat on the couch the entire day
and watched Fox News.
So, I sat down on the couch.
And she turns to me and she says, in her
old lady voice,
"It seems to me that we're turning into
a socialistic country."
And I couldn't help myself.
And I said, "I agree. I think we should
do away with socialism right now, and we
should start with this Social Security.
After all, what is Social Security but
welfare for old people who were either
too lazy or too stupid to save for their
own retirements."
And she looked at me like I was nuts,
and she said,
"That's not at all what I'm talking
about." And I said, "But Social Security
is socialism.
And so is Medicare, and so is public
education, and so is the Interstate
Highway System.
That's all socialism,
where Americans' money is pooled for the
greater good."
She didn't say a word the rest of the
day.
Well, Republicans are counting on
people being stupid
and conflating and confusing socialism
with communism. Like does anybody really
believe that the Democratic Party wants
the country to be like North Korea?
Or like Cuba?
Of course not. And that's why this thing
is not going to stick. But with that
said,
the Republicans are not going to do as
poorly in these midterm elections as
people think they are. The
million-dollar question for these
midterms coming up is will Democrat will
Democrats win enough seats
in the House and the Senate
to take control of those bodies
so that Donald Trump will either have to
change his behavior
or will be unable to get legislation
passed.
Will be unable to get his
judicial nominations through the Senate.
And could war powers resolutions and
congressional subpoena start flying?
Don't hold your breath. So, I want to
show you a chart from the Washington
Post that was published uh this past
week. The Post talked to I think it was
six different political experts. These
are people who follow congressional and
Senate races way down in the in the
weeds. These are big names like you see
Nate Silver right there. His prediction
is 11 Democrats um uh an 11-seat
Democratic pickup in the House and I'm
sorry, it was the New York Times, not
the Washington Post. 11 Democrats in the
House and that the Democrats will win
three seats in the Senate making it
even. If you go to some of JB, can you
go down to some of those others? These
are even closer. We're talking about
seven Democratic House seats and the
Republicans maintain the majority or
five Democratic House seats and the
Democrats either draw even or win a
majority of one.
Why is it still so close if Donald
Trump's approval ratings are in the
mid-30% range, which is a historic low.
It's worse than Jimmy Carter was in
1980.
Um, or yeah, I guess now it's 30 39.7.
It's still just historically low.
Um,
why are the Republicans still so close?
Oh, that's an easy one. The Republicans
are so close because the Democrats have
fallen on their faces since 1992
on redistricting.
And the reason they did that is because
a decision was made, and it was made
specifically by Hillary Clinton, who
recommended it to her husband when he
was first elected president, for the
Democrats to spend money only in states
that they could win the presidential
race in.
Okay?
So,
they didn't spend any more money in the
Dakotas, or in Kansas, or Nebraska, or
Idaho, or Montana, or any of these red
states.
Why not?
There are Democrats in those states.
And so, because the Democrats weren't
spending any money there, and
Republicans were, the Republicans were
able to elect supermajorities
in the state legislatures. That is
majorities of 2/3 or more. If you've got
a majority of 2/3, even if you have a
Democratic governor, you can override
that governor's veto.
And so, what the state legislatures then
did is they redrew
the congressional district boundaries to
elect more and more and more
Republicans.
James Carville,
um, who famously coined the phrase,
"It's the economy, stupid," and was Bill
Clinton's co-campaign manager in 1992,
um,
was apoplectic about this. He disagreed
so vehemently with Hillary Clinton, he
ended up
and not going back to the campaign.
And he still rues the day that Hillary
won that
that argument because it has set the
Democratic Party back by decades.
It's going to take decades
and billions and billions of dollars of
spending at every single level of
politics for the Democrats to recover
from this kind of thing.
And so even if the if the Democrats have
a banner year
even if Americans don't believe that the
Democratic Party is just a front for
communism, which is so laughably
preposterous. I can't believe they're
even moving forward with it.
The Republicans are probably going to be
okay
or as close to okay as possible.
Another element for the midterms right
now
is the recent success of Democratic
Socialists of America aligned
candidates, mostly in deep blue states.
Uh and the and the Republican Party is
going all in on this threat of
communism, right? We've got a clip from
Mike Johnson. Let's take a look at this
clip. I think you're going to get a kick
out of it.
>> It is a dangerous thing. This is not a
joke. We're in a fight right now to save
the republic. And every American needs
to take this seriously. You need to wake
up. This upcoming midterm election is
not the midterm elections of years ago.
This is going to decide the direction of
the country. Are we going to maintain
our status as a constitutional republic
on our 250th anniversary? Are we going
to make a new choice and go down some
road towards a communist utopia? That's
the choice.
>> Mike Johnson's an idiot.
Mike Johnson is either a liar
or he's a
I'll let you decide.
Uh
nobody's communist here. There nobody's
seeking a communist utopia. What they're
seeking is
a a broader and deeper social safety
net. And we're talking about four
people.
Four.
Out of 435.
That's less than 1%. It's actually 9/10
of 1%. So, Mike Johnson's either an
idiot or he's a liar. Frankly, me
personally, I think he's both.
So, this strategy of accusing Democrats
of being communists, um
it is really highlighting
the role of money in our elections. I
think it also highlights the fact that
the Republicans this year don't have an
issue to run on.
Um they're relying on gerrymandering to
cover them. And uh they can't they can't
tout the fact that
that MAGA
uh and the MAGA movement and their MAGA
president has kept them out of wars of
choice. He hasn't. We jumped into a war
of choice with both feet.
And so, as I said a minute ago, we
already have a partially socialist
system. That's what Social Security is.
That's what the highway system is.
That's what the Tennessee Valley
Authority is that gave electricity to
everybody in the south. That's what
public education is. That's what
Medicare and Medicaid are.
You don't like it? You're the speaker of
the house.
Take it away if you think it's
communism.
Why do you keep funding it if you think
it's communism?
Ay ay ay ay ay. Have you ever wondered
what it feels like to shoot with the
same kind of precision tech used by US
special forces? Well, good news. After
years of research and development, MCG
Tactical just dropped something
incredible. It's called the Stinger
Combat Sight. This is not your average
red dot. Using holographic technology
once reserved for elite military and law
enforcement, the Stinger delivers
crystal-clear precision. So accurate you
could hit a dime at 300 yards without
even trying.
This is the exact same level of
technology used by the pros.
But here's the twist. Most sites like
this go for 600 bucks or more, and
people happily pay it. But right now,
through an exclusive deal with MCG
Tactical, you can get this mil-spec site
for under $200.
And it gets better. For my listeners,
you're getting 67%
off, and they're covering the shipping.
This is something that
I used to use when I had my gun rights.
You have your gun rights, and it's
something you're not going to want to
miss. So, just scan the QR code or go to
mcgtac.com/johnsting
to get yours today. Again, that's
mcgtac.com/johnsting.
The only catch, supply is tight, and
these are already flying off the
shelves. So, if you want a site built
for the best, now's your shot. Grab
yours before they have to shut down
orders. That is mcgtac.com/johnsting.
I wanted to raise one other issue.
And that is the death early this morning
of former CIA director James Woolsey.
I knew James Woolsey.
Um I liked him fine.
He was only
director of Central Intelligence for 23
months, and that was at the very start
of Bill Clinton's first term.
Jim Woolsey had been a
a neoliberal hawk,
lifelong Democrat,
until he wasn't. Uh anyway, lifelong
Democrat, he had served as the secretary
of the Navy under Jimmy Carter.
And then he had several um, State
Department positions and positions in
the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency,
which no longer exists, during the
Reagan and the George H. W. Bush
administrations. He was a guy that was
respected by both parties.
And so, when Bill Clinton named him CIA
director, everybody thought, "Well, this
is this is great. Jim Woolsey's going to
be
the, um, the adult in the room."
But then a year or so after becoming the
director of Central Intelligence,
um,
the FBI arrested a traitor inside the
CIA. That was Aldrich Rick Ames.
Ames was a drunk
who had been, get this, the director of
counterintelligence
in the Soviet Operations Division.
He had access to literally
every
recruited CIA asset in the Soviet Union
and Russia.
And, surprise,
they all started dying.
Executed one by one by one.
And it was clear
that there was a spy inside the CIA. The
spy was revealed to be Rick Ames.
Jim Woolsey refused to fire,
demote, or even reassign anybody.
Now, mind you, Rick Ames had been a
drunk for decades. As part of his plea
deal, which spared him the death
penalty, he just died earlier this year
in Supermax prison in Florence,
Colorado. But as part of his plea deal,
he had to cooperate with the FBI's
investigation.
And he couldn't remember most of the
information that was necessary because
the alcohol had rotted his brain after
so many years.
But he kept getting promoted grade after
grade, after grade
at the CIA. And Jim Woolsey wouldn't
punish anybody.
And so, Bill Clinton told him, "Resign
or be fired."
And he resigned. And in a fit of pique,
he switched parties, became a
Republican, and endorsed Bob Dole in the
1996 election.
It was good for a chuckle at the CIA.
Bob Dole never had a prayer of winning
that election.
Uh Woolsey went on to vast wealth. He
became the chairman of the board of Booz
Allen Hamilton, the largest contractor
within the intelligence community, made
millions and millions of dollars. Well,
today his obituary says that officially
he died of a stroke.
But he had been suffering for 4 years
from something called Havana syndrome.
Havana syndrome is named Havana syndrome
because it first was detected outside
the American Embassy in Havana, Cuba.
It appeared to be the result of some
sort of radio waves beamed at people
that caused them not just dizziness and
nausea, but traumatic brain injuries
that have been documented through the
use of MRIs.
Um the CIA did a
an investigation
>> [clears throat]
>> and determined that no, this wasn't a
directed energy weapon. This was the
result of crickets, literally.
Because crickets chirp at this certain
frequency, and it's going in people's
brains, and it's making them crazy.
Well, that was nonsense, of course.
There are other senior former CIA
officers, Mark Polymeropoulos for one. I
I've known Mark Polymeropoulos for 35
years.
He was the sear- this the the CIA
station chief in Moscow. We were
analysts together as young kids.
He is a serious,
brilliant former CIA officer.
And he suffers from Havana syndrome, and
he has the MRI to prove it showing brain
damage.
Bill Binney,
renowned whistleblower from NSA,
the number four ranking officer in NSA
and a great hero of transparency.
He has documented brain damage from
Havana syndrome. Somebody is using these
weapons against people,
important people,
people with access to very
high-level, important, secret, highly
classified information.
We don't know who it is. The Russians,
the Chinese, the Americans,
the Israelis?
Who knows?
But Jim Woolsey's family was brave
enough and bold enough to say in his
obituary today that he was a victim of
Havana syndrome.
There's a lot going on around the world,
and one of the things that we didn't
have the time to talk about today was
news reporting that the United States
and Saudi Arabia have agreed on
a nuclear power deal.
The Saudis have been seeking nuclear
power since the 1980s.
When I first arrived at the CIA in 1990,
this was already old news. The Saudis
have always wanted to be able to enrich
uranium,
they say, to uh
develop nuclear power plants.
Why?
It's the sunniest country in the world,
and there's not a whole lot of solar
there. It's windy in the desert, and
there's not a whole lot of wind power
there.
They have um
bodies large bodies of water on two
sides, and there's not a lot of tidal
power there. Why nuclear?
Well, the conventional wisdom is already
has always been that the Saudis want to
develop a nuclear weapon.
And there have been senior former CIA
officers over the years who claim that
the Saudis already have a nuclear
weapon, that they purchased it from the
Pakistanis.
This is a story that's breaking very
slowly
and most mainstream outlets aren't
really looking at it. We're going to
talk about that. I think uh next week
we'll probably talk more about politics
and you can bet your paycheck that there
are going to be new and important
develop developments in the war with
Iran. We'll get to that as well. Ladies
and gentlemen, I want to thank you again
for
liking, commenting, sharing, and
subscribing to this podcast. Um the the
response has been absolutely
overwhelming.
As we're filming this, we're up to
144,000
subscribers. We've done that in the last
10 days.
I'm speechless, but I am deeply
grateful.
Please keep it up.
We can only do this with your help and
so thank you for allowing us the
privilege of doing it. I also would like
to point you to my other official
podcast on Apple Podcast and Spotify.
It's called John Kiriakou's Dead Drop
and you can also find me on Substack and
X and Cameo and LinkedIn and pretty much
everywhere else.
So we'll leave it there and we'll see
you next time. All the best.